DEEPAK SHARMA (1) Featured

Senior Software Engineer seeking roles in Software Engineering, Software Development, Software Design, Project Management, Change Management, Defect Management, Quality Management, Requirement Gathering, Application Support, WPF, MVVM, PRISM pattern, Oracle



Total Experience: 7 Year(s) 0 Month(s) Current Designation: Senior Software Engineer

Current Company: Continental Automotive Components Notice Period: 2 Months

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Pune

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Senior Software Engineer/Developer, Software Engineering, Software Development, Software Design, Project Management, Change Management, Defect Management, Quality Management, Requirement Gathering, Application

Support, JavaScript, ADO. Net, JIRA, SVN, SQL

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

7 years of experience in Analysis, Design and Development of Window based N-Tier Applications and applied Object Oriented design and development methodology in projects.

Proficient in WPF, MVVM, PRISM Pattern, Unity, C# 6.0, Visual Studio 2015 and SQL Server 2012, Oracle, Design Patterns and OOPS.

Knowledge of .NET Framework 3.5,4.0

4 years experience of Agile software development and software development life cycle.

Knowledge of Management tools - SVN, JIRA, and Target Process.

Visual Studio 2003.

Having good understanding of Windows Applications

Work Experience

Continental Automotive Components as Senior Software Engineer

Sep 2018 to Till Date

Conducting system study and coordinating with team members for System Design & Integration, Application Maintenance etc.

Handling various technical aspects like software design, Coding of modules, monitoring critical paths & taking appropriate actions

Execute system development and maintenance activities.

Develop solutions to improvise performance and scalability of systems.

Mind Teck as Software Engineer

Jan 2017 to Sep 2018

Conducting system study and coordinating with team members for System Design & Integration, Application Maintenance etc.

Handling various technical aspects like software design, Coding of modules, monitoring critical paths & taking appropriate

Execute system development and maintenance activities.

Develop solutions to improvise performance and scalability of systems.

Accenture as Software Engineer

Sep 2013 to May 2016

Conducting system study and coordinating with team members for System Design & Integration, Application Maintenance

Handling various technical aspects like software design, Coding of modules, monitoring critical paths & taking appropriate actions

Execute system development and maintenance activities.

Interface with clients and gather business requirements and objectives.

Develop solutions to improvise performance and scalability of systems.

Education

UG: B.Sc (Computers) from Rohilkhand University Bareilly, UP in 2006

PG: MCA (Computers) from RAJEEV GANDHI TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY BHOPAL in 2010

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience	
C#		2021	8 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
SQL Server		2013	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
JavaScript		2013	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
WPF		2021	5 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
MVVM		2021	5 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
PRISM		2021	5 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
Oracle		2021	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
hindi	Beginner			
English	Proficient			

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time